Planet of the Apes is a thriller, science fiction,
action film directed by Tim Burton.
After a spectacular crash-landing on an uncharted planet, brash astronaut Leo Davidson finds
himself trapped in a savage world where talking apes dominate the human race.
Desperate to find a way home, Leo must evade the invincible
gorilla army led by Ruthless General Thade.
Captain Leo Davidson, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Thade, played by Tim Roth.
Ari, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Attar, played by Michael Clarke Duncan.
Limbo, played by Paul Giamatti.
Daena, played by Estella Warren.
Planet of the Apes is a 2001 American science fiction action adventure film directed by Tim
Burton from a screenplay by William Broyles Jr., Lawrence Konner, and Mark Rosenthal.
The sixth installment in the Planet of the Apes film series, it is loosely based on the 1963 novel
of the same name by Pierre Boulle and serves as a remake of the 1968 film version.
The film stars Mark Wahlberg, Tim Roth, Helena Bonham Carter, Michael Clarke
Duncan, Kris Kristofferson, Estella Warren, and Paul Giamatti.
It tells the story of astronaut Leo Davidson (Wahlberg)
crash-landing on a planet inhabited by intelligent apes.
The apes treat humans as slaves, but with the help of an ape named Ari
(Bonham Carter), Leo starts a rebellion as he seeks to return.
Development for a Planet of the Apes remake started
as far back as 1988 with Adam Rifkin.
His project nearly reached the pre-production stage before being canceled.
Terry Hayes's script, titled Return of the Apes, would have starred
Arnold Schwarzenegger, under the direction of Phillip Noyce.
Oliver Stone, Don Murphy, and Jane Hamsher were set to produce.
Creative differences ensued between Hayes and 20th Century Fox.
Chris Columbus, Sam Hamm, James Cameron, Peter Jackson, and
the Hughes brothers later became involved.
With Broyles Jr.'s script, Burton was hired as director, and
the film was put into active development.
Konner and Rosenthal rewrote the script, and filming took
place from November 2000 to April 2001.
Planet of the Apes was released in the United States
on July 27, 2001, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who criticized the screenplay and twist ending, but
praised Rick Baker's prosthetic makeup designs, visual aspects, and musical score.
It grossed $362.2 million worldwide, becoming the
ninth-highest-grossing film of 2001.
Despite its financial success, Fox chose to cancel the sequel and later
rebooted the film series in 2011 with Rise of the Planet of the Apes.
The film explores themes of space marine, gorilla,
revolution, dystopia, space suit.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.